Guide to the Clifford L. Smith Photograph Collection 1916-1919
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
Clifford L. Smith Photograph Collection
1916-1919
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center Special Collections & Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu
P 037
Smith, Clifford L. (Clifford Lovejoy), 1907-
0.01 cubic foot, including 33 photographs 1 box
The Clifford L. Smith Photograph Collection consists of images assembled by Smith that document student life at Oregon Agricultural College in the late 1910s. Smith earned a B.S. from Oregon State in 1929 and joined the faculty in the early 1940s.
Biographical Note:
Clifford Lovejoy Smith was born February 23, 1907 in Kerby, Oregon. He attended Oregon Agricultural College (OAC) in 1925-1929 and received a B.S. in Dairy Husbandry in 1929. Smith was an active student at OAC and a member of the Lambda Chi Alpha fraternity.
Smith earned graduate degrees from Kansas State University (M.S., 1930) and the University of Wisconsin (Ph.D. 1959) and joined the faculty of Oregon State College in the early 1940s. He was a founding board member of the E.R. Jackman Foundation and a member of the Steak and Chop Club. Smith retired from Oregon State University on June 30, 1969 at the age of 62. He died at the age of 84 on March 8, 1991, and the “Clifford Smith Memorial Agricultural Honors Scholarship” was created in 1992 in his honor by his family.
The Clifford L. Smith Photograph Collection consists of photographs assembled by Smith that document student life at Oregon Agricultural College (OAC) in the late 1910s. Several photos are pictures of the Lambda Chi Alpha fraternity house and members. A number of photos also show many early traditions at Oregon Agricultural College, including the rook bonfire and rook-sophomore tug-of-war at the millrace. All of the items in the collection are photographic or postcard prints.
These images were made several years before Smith attended OAC; he may have acquired them through his connection with Lambda Chi Alpha fraternity.
Collection is open for research.
This collection is arranged in one series: I. Photographs.
The photographs were received by the University Archives in the 1960s.
The Special Collections & Archives Research Center includes numerous collections of photographs of student life and activities at Oregon Agricultural College in the late 1910s. Photographs of the Lambda Chi Alpha fraternity are available in the Smith-Western Company Photographs of Oregon State College (P 164) and the Fraternities and Sororities Photograph Collection (P 034) among others. The Steak and Chop Club Records (MSS Steak) document the establishment of the organization and Clifford Smith's participation.
Oregon Agricultural College--Students.; Lambda Chi Alpha.
College students--Oregon--Corvallis.; Student activities--Oregon--Corvallis.; Greek letter societies--Oregon--Corvallis.
Photographic prints.
Clubs and Societies; Student Life; Colleges and Universities; Corvallis; Oregon; Photographs
- Photographs, 1916-1919; Series I
  Series I consists of photographs of student life at Oregon Agricultural College. Some images are of waterfalls along the Columbia River Gorge.
  - Agriculture classroom, circa 1918; P037:01 (Box 1)
  - Tug of War, Junior Weekend, 1919; P037:02 (Box 1)
  - Rooks go through millrace; tug-of-war, 1919; P037:03; 2 prints (Box 1)
  - Campus Entrance, circa 1918; P037:05-P037:06 (Box 1)
  - Lambda Chi Alpha House; Winter, circa 1918; P037:07 (Box 1)
  - Kidder Hall Construction, 1918; P037:08 (Box 1)
  - Lambda Chi Alpha house, circa 1918; P037:09 (Box 1)
  - Lambda Chi Alpha members on steps of house, 1918; P037:10 (Box 1)
  - Guarding the Lady of the Fountain, circa 1918; P037:11-P037:12 (Box 1)
  - Latourell Falls, Columbia River Highway, circa 1918; P037:13 (Box 1)
  - Oneonta Gorge from Columbia River Highway, circa 1918; P037:14 (Box 1)
  - Luncheon at Oneonta Gorge Columbia Highway, circa 1918; P037:15 (Box 1)
  - Multnomah Falls, Columbia Highway, circa 1918; P037:16 (Box 1)
  - Initiation of 1922 Vigilance Committee, 1919; P037:17 (Box 1)
  - Tug of war; Loyal Sophomores, circa 1918; P037:19 (Box 1)
  - Rook team; tug of war, circa 1918; P037:20 (Box 1)
    Hiatt, Rose, Webster, Daigh, Grayton, and Perry.
  - Annual rook sophomore tug of war, circa 1918; P037:20A; 2 prints (Box 1)
  - Rook sophomore tug of war, circa 1918; P037:20B; 2 prints (Box 1)
    Sophomores in the millrace.
  - Burning the green caps; class of 1920, circa 1917; P037:21; 2 prints (Box 1)
  - Green cap crematory, circa 1918; P037:22 (Box 1)
  - Rook bonfire, circa 1918; P037:23-P037:24 (Box 1)
  - Some of OAC students, 1916; P037:25 (Box 1)
  - Company B, First Battalion, ROTC cadets, 1916; P037:26 (Box 1)
  - Lambda Chi Alpha Installation, circa 1918; P037:27 (Box 1)
  - Orson Strahn, circa 1918; P037:28 (Box 1)
  - Umatilla Club at the time it became Lambda Chi Alpha, circa 1918; P037:29 (Box 1)
  - Lambda Chi Alpha House party, circa 1918; P037:30 (Box 1)